

- **\(+1 (504) 333-9446**
- nguyen.rickyh@gmail.com
- San Diego, California, USA
- ☐ rnguyen6.github.io

SUMMARY

Computer engineer with experience in field installation, maintaining lifecycle, and improving quality of customer data networks and its interconnected systems. Demonstrated ability to provide local and distance (remote and travel) support on troubleshooting hardware and software pertaining to workstation PCs, server and domains, and electrical amplifiers. Strong knowledge of network cable plant design processes including fiber optic and copper installation, security through access control lists and internet protocols, and vulnerability control through information assurance (IA) hardening.

EDUCATION

MS in Computer Engineering [GPA: 3.65] | Illinois Institute of Technology

Chicago, IL

May 2019

Concentration: Computer Hardware Design

Coursework: VLSI Systems Design, Computer Architecture, Hardware Software Codesign, Operating System Design, Computer Network Security, Wireless Networking, Digital Systems-on-Chip Design

BS in Computer Engineering [GPA: 3.70] | Illinois Institute of Technology

Chicago, IL

May 2018

Coursework: Circuit Analysis, Digital Systems, Microcomputers, Signals Systems, VLSI Design, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Systems Programming, Operating Systems, Database Organization

EXPERIENCE

Systems Engineer II | Raytheon

San Diego, CA

Aug 2019 - Present

- Field engineer supporting radar systems, wide area networks, machinery & ship control, and voice & video systems
- Responsible engineering agent and/or subject matter expert for 5 hull, mechanical, and electrical (HM&E) systems
- Provides customer assistance in IA hardening and troubleshooting for shipboard electronics of 10 ships
- Developed, tested, and maintained the upgraded intranet for the HM&E systems of 4 ships
- Alteration and installation team (AIT) lead of major network modifications for 2 ships spanning year long installs
- Completed over 400 computer deliverables, from lab construction and load to field test and maintenance

CS Teacher Assistant | Illinois Institute of Technology

Chicago, IL Jan 2016 - Feb 2019

- Assisted approximately 30 students per semester in introductory computer science object-oriented programming
- Led weekly lab sessions, answering questions and concerns in the Java and Python languages
- Reselected as a preferred applicant 6 consecutive semesters until graduation

Image and Electronic Systems Expert | IIT UAV Experimentalists

Chicago, IL Aug 2016 - June 2017

- Collaborated in constructing an unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) emphasizing production speed and modularity
- Designed the imaging systems for autonomous object avoidance and assisted in cyber security protocols
- Participated in the 2017 AUVSI SUAS competition at Naval Air Station in Patuxent River, MD

LiCoO₂ Chemist | High-Power Li-Ion Batteries Project

Chicago, IL Jan 2017 - May 2017

- Collaborated in composing lithium ion batteries capable of fast recharge while maintaining voltage
- Iterated over 20 batches of nano-LiCoO₂, varying particle size and composite to minimize diffusion distance
- Awarded Dean's Choice Award and Track Award at Spring 2017 IIT IPRO Day

Electronics Repair Technician | Freelance

New Orleans, LA Aug 2011 - May 2014

- Provided services to troubleshoot consumer hardware, modify software, and add artistic modifications
- Specialized in repairing mobile cell phones, video game consoles, and other small consumer electronics

Subject Expert Tutor | Patrick Taylor Academy

New Orleans, LA Aug 2012 - May 2014

- Assisted students in elementary mathematics and sciences, specializing in Calculus and Physics
- Provided 2 sessions every week with individualized teaching regimen per student

SKILLS

VHDL, Verilog, Assembly (MIPS) ModelSim, Virtuoso, HSpice Autodesk Inventor (CAD), Blender Java & Python C, C#, C++ HTML & CSS OmniVista (Alcatel)
PuTTy & SSH
LaTeX & R

Microsoft Office
Mathematica & MatLab
Rhinoceros 3D